Adrian Fusco



adrianfuscoarnejo@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/adrianfusco



https://adrianfusco.github.io/

Summary

I started to work in the computer science area four years ago. I did a system administrator professional development (CFGS in Spain) and after some time I changed to the development area. I realized that I can't stay just in one area, I like to do and learn a lot of different things.

I had more than two years working as Backend Developer. I started working mainly with the Perl language and after a big migration of technology and services I used PHP and Python where I had the opportunity of learn a lot and grow up.

Almost two years ago I had a big change, I joined to Red Hat, I think the name can tell everything:).

I'm currently working with the Code Reliability Engineering team improving the CI systems (and other areas) of the Openstack infrastructure both upstream and downstream.

A good fan about contributions in open source community.

Experience



Red Hat

Sep 2022 - Present (6 months)

- Contribution in the Openshift project adding components of Openstack as k8s operators and creating jobs in Prow CI.
- Contribution in different upstream and downstream projects using mainly Go and Python programming language.
- Automation with Ansible and addition of Ansible molecule for testing roles.
- Bash scripting & work on Makefiles.
- GitHub Actions.

Associate Software Engineer

Red Hat

Nov 2021 - Sep 2022 (11 months)

Working mainly with the Code Reliability Engineering Team in a global environment with people from different countries.

- Collaboration in upstream and downstream projects in the same and other teams.
- Experience with CI systems creating pipelines on Jenkins and workflows in GitHub repositories.
- Experience with Python development (which is used in a high percentage across the OpenStack community).
- Experience with agile and scrum development methodologies.
- Improvement and troubleshooting using the ELK Stack + Beats + Data manipulation using painless scripting in DSL queries.

- Working on Grafana visualizations + Telegraf + InfluxDB.

Backend Developer (Full remote)

Dinahosting S.L.

Aug 2019 - Nov 2021 (2 years 4 months)

PHP & Perl developer. I also work with Go and Python in few projects.

- Web, user control panel and public and private APIs development. I've worked with Zend 2 and Symfony 4 and 5.
- Implementation of AWStats authentication system.
- SSL External Certificates installation automation on Linux servers from user control panel.
- Services and processes automation.
- Creation of development environments using Docker (docker-compose and Dockerfile). I also work with Docker Swarm.
- Improvements on new backup control system using different technologies like Restic, Ceph, Perl frameworks like Mojolicious.
- I've worked with another technologies like ansible and ELK stack.
- I've worked with Xen and KVM technologies using modules like Libvirt for processes automation.
- Troubleshooting: Technical issues resolution in our website, panel control, public and private APIs and linux servers.
- Continuous integration with Gitlab CI.
- Using version control like Git.

Linux Technical Support

Dinahosting S.L.

May 2019 - Aug 2019 (4 months)

- -Customer support via e-mail, calls and live chat.
- -Troubleshooting server issues in:
- -Web services (apache, nginx).
- -HTTP accelerator/reverse proxy (varnish).
- -Mail services (postfix, dovecot).
- -Database services (MySQL/MariaDB)
- -Content Management Systems (Wordpress, Prestashop, Moodle, Joomla, ...)
- -Firewalls.



Pub/Restaurant Waiter

Café Bar París

Jun 2018 - Jun 2019 (1 year 1 month)

- -Customer support.
- -Pub/Restaurant Waiter.
- -Work area preparation.

Intern - Linux Technical Support

Dinahosting S.L.

Mar 2019 - May 2019 (3 months)

-Learning everything about all the internal system and company services.

- -Customer support via e-mail, calls and live chat.
- -Troubleshooting server issues.

Education

Universitat Oberta de Catalunya

Computer Science Degree, Computer Science 2019 - 2024

IES Xulian Magariños

System Administration Professional Development (CFGS in Spain)

2017 - 2019

- -Database Managment
- -Database Administration.
- -Network & Internet Services.
- -Network security & High Availibility
- -Operative Systems Administration & Implementation.
- -Markup languages.
- -Information management systems.
- -Network planification.
- -Network administration.
- -Webservices implementation.
- -Training and career counseling.
- -Entrepreneurship.

Licenses & Certifications

Linux Professional Institute Level 2 Exam 201-450, Pearson VUE and LPI. - Linux Professional Institute (LPI)

Issued Jun 2018 - Expires Jun 2021

- PCEP Certified Entry-Level Python Programmer OpenEDG Python Institute 8pxp.9i0P.dSl3
- PCAP Certified Associate in Python Programming OpenEDG Python Institute dAV8.PkB9.RrK5
- in Learning Jenkins (2018) LinkedIn
- in Learning the Elastic Stack LinkedIn
- B2.2 Upper Intermediate English Level Escuela Oficial de Idiomas

- in Learning Kubernetes LinkedIn
- in Learning Terraform LinkedIn

Skills

Python • Linux • Bash • Linux Containers • Programación • Desarrollo de software • Microsoft SQL Server • PHP • Windows Server • JavaScript